Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, Subject Files, 1963-present UPG.RG.52
ULS Greensburg
- UPG Theater Dept. Productions, 2004-present (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 3, Map-case 1)
  2010, March 24-27. Urinetown, The Musical. Music by Mark Hollman, Lyrics by Mark Hollman & Greg Kotis, Book by Greg Kotis. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 14A,B. Urinetown
  2010/2011 Season
  Touring Production, The Telltale Poe [UPG News Release 9/20/10]
  Play it Again, Sam. Entered in KCACTF (Kennedy Center American College Theatre Festival [UPG News Release 9/29/10]
  Pitt-Greensburg Theatre Company to Present "You Can't Take It With You" [News Release 3/23/11]
  2010, November 18-20. Play it Again, Sam by Woody Allen. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 15 A, B. Play it Again, Sam
  2011, March 31, April 1-2. You Can't Take it With You by Moss Hart & George Kaufman. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 16, You Can't Take it With You.
  2011/12 Season ["Origin and Invention"]
  News Release: 10/27/11 Pitt-Greensburg Theatre Company to perform Greek tragedy.
  News Release: 4/10/12 Media Alert: The Red Eye Project
  2011, Nov. 17, 18, 19, 20. Hippolytus by Euripides. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD20, Hippolytus.
  2011, Dec. 1-2 Prometheus Bound by Aeschylus. [A blended reality event performed in the online 3D world of Second Life. UPG Ferguson Theater, Dec. 1-2, 2011. For DVD, See: RG60 DVD 22 Prometheus Bound
  2012, Mar. 22-25. Dog Assassin created by Stephen Schrum with collaborator Jeremy dePrisco. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 21A,B Dog Assassin
  2012, Apr. 14-15. Red Eye Project [creates drama in 24 hours].
  2012/13 Season
  2012, Nov. 15-18. Arsenic and Old Lace by Joseph Kesserling. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 26 Arsenic and Old Lace
  2013, Feb. 16-17. Red Eye Project (2nd Annual)
  2013, Apr. 4-5. Eleanor: An American Love Story. Music by Thomas Tierney, Lyrics by John Forster, Book by Jonathan Bolt. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD 27, Eleanor: An American Love Story
  2013/14 Season
  2013, Nov. 21-24. The Birth of Merlin or, The Child has Found His Father. By William Shakespeare & William Rowley. Prologue and Song Lyrics by Stephen A. Schrum; Song Melodies by Bethany M. Thomas. The Pitt-Greensburg Theatre Company. Nov. 21, 23, 24, 2013. Ferguson Theater. See also: UPG.RG.52 Ser.: UPG Theater Dept. Productions. Season 2013/2014. The Birth of Merlin... [For DVD of Promo Videos of The Birth of Merlin See, UPG.RG.60 DVD28 The Birth of Merlin [Promo Videos.] [For performance of The Birth of Merlin See UPG.RG.60 DVD28A The Birth of Merlin. Fall 2013.]
  2014, Apr. 3-5. A Night of Magic featuring A Very Potter Musical (music and lyrics by Darren Criss and A.J. Holmes, book by Matt Lang, Nick Lang, and Brian Holden.) For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD30 A Very Potter Musical.
  2014/2015 Season 2014, Nov. 20-23. 'Rabbit Hole by David Linsdsay-Adair. 2015, Mar. 26-29. Chemical Imbalance: A Jekyll and Hyde Play by Lauren Wilson. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD35 Chemical Imbalance: A Jekyll and Hyde Play.
  2015/2016 Season 2015, Nov. 19-22, Middletown by Will Eno. 2016, Apr. 7-10. Man From La Mancha written by Dale Wasserman with music by Mitch Leigh and lyrics by Joe Darion. For DVD: See: UPG.RG.60 DVD33A (Act 1), DVD33B (Act 2).
  2016/2017 Season 2016, Nov., 17-20. An Evening of One Act Plays: The Precious Damsels Ridiculed by Moliere; Shakespeare's Ladies Meet by Charles George; a world premier of a new play, 15 Frogs and Counting, written and directed by Kaitlyn Schmidt, senior UPG Visual and Peforming Arts major.
  2017, Mar. 30-Apr. 2. Shakespeare in Hollywood by Ken Ludwig. For DVD, See: UPG.RG.60 DVD36 Shakespeare in Hollywood.
  2017/2018 Season "Invisible Voices" 2017, Sept. 12. In the Year of Perfect Vision. A reading of a play written by Stephen Schrum and Fred Birk in 1985 "imagining what a gathering of their friends would be in 35 years in the future...presented as originally written, with no changes." UPG Ferguson Theatre, Sept. 12, 2017. 2017, Nov. 16-19. Harvey by Mary Chase. 2018, Mar. 22-25. The Tempest by William Shakespeare.
  2018/2019 Season Note: ["..."Universal Monsters", overall theme selected for the 2018/2019 theater season...".] 2018, Nov. 15-18. Dracula by contemporary playwright Steven Dietz. 2019, Apr. 4-7. Young Frankenstein: The Musical by Mel Brooks and Thomas Meehan. 2019, Feb. 8. Neighboring Chat by Alex Obringer. [A staged reading of Creative and Professional Writing Major Alex Obringer.]
  2019/2020 Season 2019, Nov. 14-17. Chekhov in Yalta written by John Driver & Jeffrey Haddow.
- University Scholars (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  See: UPG.RG.52 Subject Files, Ser.: Honors Convocation. [Programs 2002- ]
- Veterans Services [University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Veterans Services] (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  See also UPG.RG.52 Salute Veterans Honor Society; UPG.RG.52 Graduating Military.
- Veterans Week--Pitt-Greensburg, 2018-2019 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  2018, Nov. 5-9 2019, Nov. 11-15
- Veterans Writing Workshop Series, October 9, 2017 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  Initiative launched in October 2017 "with free weekly workshops to help the veteran community tell their stories." Officially began, Monday, October 9. 2017.
- Vira I. Heinz Scholarship [International Study Awards], 2010-2019 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  2010 Glera Jupiter; Christina Mizer; Chelsea Walker 2011 Allison Brichacek, Kelsey Salerno, Nicole Williams 2012 Angel Rohal, Sarah Adams 2013 Alicia DiPaolo, Lauren Fawcett, Bethany Hallam, Alaina Kling 2014 (No listing in 2014 Honors Convocation program. faz) 2015 Ariane Autore, Kiersten Brown, Cassandra Foradori, Ashley Muscarella 2016 Sade Banks, Leigha Bucks, Michele Etling, Nichole Johnson, Amanda Sepp 2017 Madison Bredice, Corinne Kirk, Kasey McIntosh, Chelsea Sundy 2018 Aponi Geletko, Chelsea Holmes, Samantha Ursiney 2019 Aniya Haley, Allyson Hall, Courtney Weinell
- Voice Masterclass Recital [The University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Interdisciplinary Arts Program], April 4, 2011 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
- Walk to Cure Diabetes (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
- Westmoreland Forum (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
- Westmoreland Heritage (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
- Westmoreland Walks: Taking Steps Against Cancer, Sept. 23-28, 2002 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  1st Annual.
- Women's History Month, 1999-2019 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  1999, 2000, 2001, 2003, 2004, 2007, 2008, 2019
- World Trade Center, Terrorist Attack on., September 11, 2001 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  Includes: Comments, via e-mail, to the University of Pittsburgh University Community from Chancellor Mark A. Nordenberg; remarks by UPG President Frank A. Cassell at the Sept. 17, 2001 memorial service for the victims of the Sept. 11 attack; copies of various campus e-mail in re the event; newspaper clippings; program for the Memorial Services held Sept. 17, 2001 at noon. Includes: flyer, "UPG Remembers 9.11, a noon-rembrance ceremony 9/11 2002"; file contains a DVD copy of the "World Trade Center Tribute 9/11/2001".
- Writers Festival [Pitt-Greensburg Writers Festival; Creative Nonfiction Week; Creative Nonfiction Week and Literary Festival; Creative and Professional Writing Prizes], 2004-2016 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  NOTE: Debuted in 2001. "When the festival debuted in 2001, it was limited to creative non-fiction. Since then it has expanded into a week-long festival that crosses all genres." Source: Lori Jakiela quoted in The [UPG] Insider 3/22/10.
  Archives holds information for:
  2004, April 5-9 2005, Feb. 14-17 2006, Feb. 13-17 2007, Mar. 12-16 2008, Mar. 24-28 2009, Mar. 16-21 2010, Mar. 22-16 2011, Mar. 14-18 2012, April 9-12 2013, April 8-11 2014, April 7-11 2015, April 6-10 2016, April 11-15 See also: UPG Special Collections: PS504.R68 2016 Route 30: Poems, Stories, and Essays ed. by Michelle Boring and Lori Jakiela.
- Written/Spoken Reading Series (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
- You Make The Difference Recognition Program for the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Staff, 2000 (Museum-cabinet 2, Shelf 7, Box 4)
  Replaced the "Pitt Pat" Award Program in Oct., 2000.